Guide to the Julius J. Spector Collection ARS.0013
Archive of Recorded Sound
Julius J. Spector Collection
1934-1998
Archive of Recorded Sound
Spector, Julius J.
ARS.0013
12.5 Linear Feet
The collection contains approximately 500 LP discs, 428 open reel tapes, 75 audiocassettes, and 45 videocassettes, correspondence, photographs and other paper materials. The materials are housed in 11 record storage boxes and 1 document storage box, for a total of 12.5 linear feet.
Separated Materials note
The LP discs (approximately 500) were interfiled with the ARS LP collection.
Arrangement note
Correspondence, photographs, and other paper materials have been filed in a single box. Audio tapes have been organized alphabetically by composer name.
Scope and Contents note
Collection includes typed and handwritten correspondence, signed photographs from persons prominent in the classical music world, a typed script for a speech on Toscanini, and a limited-edition copy of Arthur Schnabel's "Reflections on Music," signed by the author. Audio tapes in the collection contain various broadcast performances of operas and concerts between 1955 and 1996. VHS tapes contain primarily operas but also several concert performances, all dating from the mid 1980s through the 1990s.
Biographical/Historical note
Julius J. Spector attended Fordham University and studied art at Cooper Union, later finding employment in New York-based advertising agencies; he later gained prominence in the direct marketing industry. Spector once worked as an extra in New York City Opera productions, played the clarinet, and in the course of his lifetime befriended many prominent musicians.
Source
The Julius J. Spector Collection was donated the Stanford Archive of Recorded Sound by Eric Spector in 2004.
Musicians -- Portraits; Operas; Sound recordings; Videocassettes; Spector, Julius J.
- Papers, 1934-1968 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1938-1968; 7 typescript or handwritten letters (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    Typescript or handwritten letters from Willem Mengelberg, Olga Samaroff Stokowski, Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco, "Arthur or Artur" Rubinstein, C. H. Clemens, Walter Toscanini.
  - Photographs, 12 photographs: chiefly black and white (Box 1, Folder 2)
    12 signed photographs (chiefly black and white) of John Barbirolli, Thomas Beecham, Phyllis Diller, Kirsten Flagstad, Glenn Ford, Giovanni Martinelli, Lauritz Melchior, Willem Mengelberg, Luciano Pavarotti, Friedrich Schorr, Jean Sibelius, and Bruno Walter. An additional signed portrait of Mengelberg is located in the ARS Posters/Prints Box #1.
  - Schnabel: Reflections on Music, 1934; 1 book(s); no content (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Copy no. 30 of a limited edition of 200. Signed by the author.
    Music -- History and criticism; Schnabel, Artur, 1882-1951
  - Chotzinoff speech, 25 leaves (typescript); no content (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Typescript of speech, "Our need for Toscanini," composed for the America-Italy Society.
    Chotzinoff, Samuel; America-Italy Society
  - Misc. papers, ca. 1940-1960; [20?] leaves + 1 booklet (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Copies of newspaper reviews; list of Toscanini recordings available on full track tapes; program for Rigoletto, presented by the San Carlo Opera Co. at the Center Theater (NY) signed by John Barrymore and Elaine Barrie.
    San Carlo Opera Company
- Audio tapes, open reel, 1955-1996
  - Open reel tapes, Ba-Bi (Box 2)
  - Open reel tapes, Bi-Go (Box 3)
  - Open reel tapes, H-Me (Box 4)
  - Open reel tapes, Mo-O (Box 5)
  - Open reel tapes, P-Ro (Box 6)
  - Open reel tapes, Ro-Tc (Box 7)
  - Open reel tapes, Tc-Ve (Box 8)
  - Open reel tapes, Ve-Wa (Box 9)
  - Open reel tapes, Wa-Z (Box 10)
- Audio tapes, cassettes, 1987-1995
  - Cassettes, 1987-1993 (Box 11, Carton 1)
  - Cassettes, 1988-1995 (Box 11, Carton 2)
- Video tapes (VHS), 1980s-1990s
  - VHS tapes: opera performances (Box 11)
  - VHS tapes: opera and other live performances (Box 12)